ADRIAN IKE BARRANCO

Taylorsville, UT, 84129

Phone: 385-229-7480 | Email: <u>barranco.ike@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ike-barranco/ | GitHub: https://github.com/ikemous | Portfolio:

https://ikemous.herokuapp.com/

SUMMARY

Variety IT specialist with over two years of experience in System Administration, Network Administration, CNOC Monitoring, troubleshooting and various coding languages. Trained to and deployed Cisco devices while deployed with the Utah Army National Guard. Completed Trilogy's 24 Week Coding Bootcamp

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, APIs, Node.js, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose,

Handlebars, React.js

Applications: Git, Visual Studio Code, MySQL Workbench

PROJECTS

Burger Logger | https://github.com/ikemous/burger logger | https://buger-eater.herokuapp.com/

- Website to store and delete burger names from database
- Full stack developer
- Technologies: JavaScript, jQuery, Node, Express, Handlebars, MySQL, CSS, HTML

Movie Lover | https://github.com/Robbie2497/Project-2 | https://projectdash.herokuapp.com/

- Website to search movies by name and then save them to view later
- Responsibilities were assigned through project cards in GitHub.
- Technologies: JavaScript, jQuery, API, Node, Express, Handlebars, Sequelize, CSS, HTML

Grocery List Generator | https://github.com/fftab/Grocery-List | https://fftab.github.io/Grocery-List/

- Website to search for recipes by ingredient. You then can save the recipe for a grocery list
- GitHub Project creator/manager and JavaScript developer
- Technologies: API, JavaScript, jQuery, Project, CSS, HTML

Team Generator|https://github.com/ikemous/GUI-team-generator|https://dev-team-generator.herokuapp.com/

- Website to enter team information and develop a html page with the team's information.
- Full stack developer
- Technologies: JavaScript, ¡Query, Node, Express, CSS, HTML

EXPERIENCE

Network Operation Center Monitor 2020 – Current

Conduent Sandy, UT

- Verify issues are occurring using SolarWinds, Netcool and LiveNX
- Use networking devices to troubleshoot and find more information on downed items
- Use ServiceNow to create/track issues
- Communicate with various Internet Service Providers for connection verification
- Create tickets using Internet Service Provider ticketing systems
- Actively communicate with multiple IT departments
- Conduent CNOC SharePoint Committee member

Information Technology Specialist 2018 – Current Utah Army National Guard Camp Williams, UT

- Troubleshoot software and hardware
- Replace or upgrade hardware
- Configure and maintain Cisco routers and switches
- Troubleshoot Network issues using Cisco and Satellite devices
- Document and maintain network flow diagrams
- Create detailed shift notes on issues/resolutions occurred during shifts
- Use section made or Remedy Ticketing Systems to create/track issues
- Configure General Dynamic TACLANES and fill with encryption
- Network/System administrator for several locations
- Helpdesk services for over 100 soldiers supporting multiple locations

Help Desk Technician L1 2019 – 2020

TEKsystems Sandy, UT

- Customer service call center helpdesk technician
- Use ServiceNow ticketing system to create tickets
- Remotely troubleshoot software/hardware issues

RSP Administration Specialist 2015 – 2018 Utah Army National Guard Camp Williams, UT

- Administrative Specialist for over 200 soldiers
- Initial entry training career advisor
- Use Army Pay Management System to issue pay or fix pay issues
- Check numerous documents to ensure 100% accuracy with the soldier's information
- Create/instruct training for initial entry training soldiers
- Obtained expert drivers' badge for being lead vehicle operator for transportation of soldiers and office/training equipment

EDUCATION

Trilogy Coding Bootcamp, Certification: University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT (2020-2020)

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Computer Science w/ Emphasis in Programming, Bachelors: American Public University, Charles Town WV (2018-2022)

72/120 Credits Complete

Information Technology Specialist(25B), Certification: Army, Camp Williams UT (2018-2018)

Computer Science, Bachelors: Utah Valley University, Provo UT (2017-2018)

General Education: Salt Lake Community College, Salt Lake City UT (2016-2017)